{
  "questions" : 
  [
    {
      "Category" : 2,
      "Question number" : 1,
      "Question Name" : "Alternate the glasses",
      "Question" : "Six identical glasses are in a row. The first three glasses are filled with juice, and the last three glasses are empty.\nWhich glass should you move so that the full and the empty glasses are alternate?",
      "Hint" : "You have to pour the contents of one glass into another",
      "Answer" : 1,
      "Explanation" : "After you empty the contents of glass 2 into glass 5, glasses 1, 3 and 5 will be full.",
      "Message" : "Thirsty?",
      "Pad Characters" : "",
      "Options" : 
      [
        2,
        3,
        5,
        6
      ],
      "Layout type" : 0
    },
    {
      "Category" : 1,
      "Question number" : 2,
      "Question Name" : "How many months?",
      "Question" : "Some months have 30 days, some months have 31 days. How many months have 28 days?",
      "Hint" : "Think more",
      "Answer" : 12,
      "Explanation" : "All months have 28 days",
      "Message" : "",
      "Pad Characters" : "",
      "Options" : "",
      "Layout type" : 2
    },
    {
      "Category" : 1,
      "Question number" : 3,
      "Question Name" : "Feeling ill?",
      "Question" : "If a doctor gives you 3 pills and tells you to take one pill every half hour, how long would it be before all the pills had been taken?",
      "Hint" : "Try it out",
      "Answer" : 1,
      "Explanation" : "Some time later",
      "Message" : "",
      "Pad Characters" : "",
      "Options" : 
      [
        0.5,
        1,
        1.5,
        2
      ],
      "Layout type" : 0
    },
    {
      "Category" : 2,
      "Question number" : 4,
      "Question Name" : "Divide and conquer",
      "Question" : "Divide 30 by half and add ten. What do you get?",
      "Hint" : "use BODMAS",
      "Answer" : 4,
      "Explanation" : "30 divide by half is 60. 60+10=70",
      "Message" : "",
      "Pad Characters" : "",
      "Options" : 
      [
        25,
        50,
        35,
        70
      ],
      "Layout type" : 0
    },
    {
      "Category" : 2,
      "Question number" : 5,
      "Question Name" : "Sheepish",
      "Question" : "A farmer had 17 sheep. All but 9 died. How many live sheep were left?",
      "Hint" : "Read second statement carefully",
      "Answer" : 9,
      "Explanation" : "All died except for those 9",
      "Message" : "",
      "Pad Characters" : "",
      "Options" : 
      [
        7,
        8,
        9,
        10
      ],
      "Layout type" : 0
    },
    {
      "Category" : 2,
      "Question number" : 6,
      "Question Name" : "Dark room",
      "Question" : "If you had only one match and entered a COLD and DARK room, where there was an oil heater, an oil lamp and a candle, which would you light first?",
      "Hint" : "Think of all the possibilities",
      "Answer" : "match",
      "Explanation" : "You have to light the match first",
      "Message" : "",
      "Pad Characters" : "canhltdecm",
      "Options" : "",
      "Layout type" : 2
    },
    {
      "Category" : 1,
      "Question number" : 7,
      "Question Name" : "Speling bee",
      "Question" : "There is one eleven letter word, which can be spelled incorrectly even by the most brilliant students, what word it that?",
      "Hint" : "Answer is in the question itself",
      "Answer" : "incorrectly",
      "Explanation" : "You would have got it by now",
      "Message" : "",
      "Pad Characters" : "inctlyrcore",
      "Options" : "",
      "Layout type" : 2
    },
    {
      "Category" : 0,
      "Question number" : 1,
      "Question Name" : "S",
      "Question" : "16, 33, 65, 131, 261, (....)",
      "Hint" : "Multiply and add/subtract",
      "Answer" : 523,
      "Explanation" : "Each number is double the previous with 1 added and subtracted alternatively",
      "Message" : "",
      "Pad Characters" : " ",
      "Options" : 391522523521,
      "Layout type" : 0
    },
    {
      "Category" : 0,
      "Question number" : 2,
      "Question Name" : "E",
      "Question" : "8, 7, 11, 12, 14, 17, 17, 22, (....)",
      "Hint" : "2 sequences in one?",
      "Answer" : 20,
      "Explanation" : "One sequence is 8, 11, 14, 17 and other is 7, 12, 17, 22",
      "Message" : "",
      "Pad Characters" : " ",
      "Options" : 
      [
        22,
        27,
        25,
        20
      ],
      "Layout type" : 0
    },
    {
      "Category" : 0,
      "Question number" : 3,
      "Question Name" : "Q",
      "Question" : "11, 13, 17, 19, 23, 29, 31, 37, 41, (....)",
      "Hint" : "What sort of numbers are these",
      "Answer" : 43,
      "Explanation" : "All are prime numbers",
      "Message" : "",
      "Pad Characters" : " ",
      "Options" : 
      [
        43,
        45,
        44,
        47
      ],
      "Layout type" : 0
    },
    {
      "Category" : 0,
      "Question number" : 4,
      "Question Name" : "U",
      "Question" : "2, 6, 12, 20, 30, 42, 56, (....)",
      "Hint" : "The 99th number is 9900 ",
      "Answer" : 72,
      "Explanation" : "Numbers are 1*2, 2*3,..",
      "Message" : "",
      "Pad Characters" : " ",
      "Options" : 
      [
        70,
        68,
        72,
        74
      ],
      "Layout type" : 0
    },
    {
      "Category" : 0,
      "Question number" : 5,
      "Question Name" : "E",
      "Question" : "31,28,31,30,31,30,31,31,30,31,30,(...)",
      "Hint" : "Not numerical but maybe you see your knuckles to remember this",
      "Answer" : 31,
      "Explanation" : "Number of days in each month",
      "Message" : "",
      "Pad Characters" : " ",
      "Options" : 
      [
        28,
        29,
        30,
        31
      ],
      "Layout type" : 0
    },
    {
      "Category" : 0,
      "Question number" : 6,
      "Question Name" : "N",
      "Question" : "0,1,1,2,3,5,8,13,21,34,(...)",
      "Hint" : "Do you know fibonacci?",
      "Answer" : 55,
      "Explanation" : "Each number is the sum of the previous two",
      "Message" : "",
      "Pad Characters" : " ",
      "Options" : 
      [
        47,
        34,
        55,
        65
      ],
      "Layout type" : 0
    },
    {
      "Category" : 0,
      "Question number" : 7,
      "Question Name" : "C",
      "Question" : "2,3,5,13,89,(...)",
      "Hint" : "Intersection of two previous sequences",
      "Answer" : 131,
      "Explanation" : "These are the prime numbers in the fibonacci sequence",
      "Message" : "",
      "Pad Characters" : " ",
      "Options" : 
      [
        91,
        95,
        129,
        131
      ],
      "Layout type" : 0
    },
    {
      "Category" : 0,
      "Question number" : 8,
      "Question Name" : "E",
      "Question" : "A,E,F,K,L,M,N,(...)",
      "Hint" : "These letters have something in common in the way they are written",
      "Answer" : "T",
      "Explanation" : "Letters made up of entirely straight lines",
      "Message" : "",
      "Pad Characters" : "OPQRSTUV",
      "Options" : "",
      "Layout type" : 1
    }
  ]}
